Finding aid for John Duke papers CA.MS.00066
Smith College Archives
- Series VI. RECORDINGS, 1939-1984
  - Tapes: Reel-to-Reel
    - Songs, miscellaneous (Box 42)
      - Lynn Meyers and John Duke (Part 1 of 2), 1965 Nov 7 (Box 42)
      - Seagle Colony, 1954 Aug (Box 42)
      - Rod Gisick, 1974 Oct 9 (Box 42)
      - Elizabeth Kirkpatrick, Don Boothman, and John Duke, 1978 Nov 5 (Box 42)
      - "The Performing Voice," WFCR radio (2 tapes), 1967 Mar 29 (Box 42)
      - Natina Bryan, Adrienne Auerswald, and John Duke (Box 42)
      - Oren Brown Seminar, 1974 Aug 13 (Box 42)
      - Jon Humphrey and Fernande Kaeser, undated (Box 42)
      - Lynn Meyers and John Duke, undated (Box 42)
      - WNYC Festival of American Music, Dorothy Stahl and John Duke, 1957 Feb 17 (Box 42)
      - Marjorie McClung, 1960 Dec 19 (Box 42)
      - Frederick Frey, 1975 Feb 15 (Box 42)
      - Richard Rivers, Claudia Bray, John Hanks, and John Duke, 1963 Nov 5 (Box 42)
      - Richard Rivers and John Duke, 1970 Apr 15 (Box 42)
      - Richard Rivers and John Duke, 1963 Nov 8 (Box 42)
      - Patricia Scheuer, 1983 Nov 4 (Box 42)
      - Oren Brown Seminar, John and Gretchen D'Armand, 1972 Aug 10 (Box 42)
      - Phyllis Paige and John Duke (3 tapes), 1980 Aug (Box 42)
      - Jon Humphrey and Fernande Kaiser, "3 Chinese Love Lyrics" (Box 42)
      - Lynn Meyers and John Duke, "4 Chinese Love Lyrics" (Part 2 of 2), 1965 Nov 7 (Box 42)
      - Phyllis Paige, n3 songs in Praise of Death"; "String Quartet No. 28", undated (Box 42)
      - Lauralyn Kolb and John Duke, "Good Morning!", 1974 Apr 29 (Box 42)
      - Deborah Noorefield, "6 poems by Emily Dickinson", 1977 Feb 15 (Box 43)
      - Adrienne Auerewald and John Duke, "6 poems by Emily Dickinson", undated (Box 43)
      - Adrienne Auerswald and Robert Miller, "6 poems by Emily Dickinson", 1969 Oct 19 (Box 43)
      - Jenny Harriman and Patty Applegate, "Mignon Songs", 1974 Nov 21 (Box 43)
      - John D'Armand and Dwight Peltzer, "The Ballad of Jiminy Trout", undated (Box 43)
      - Dorothy Stahl, Louise Rood, and John Duke, "3 sonnets by Edna St. Vincent Millay", 1959 Oct 23 (Box 43)
      - Jenny Harriman and Patty Applegate, "Mignon Songs", 1975 Jan 27 (Box 43)
      - Barbara Staropoli and Richard Wolfe, "6 poems by Emily Dickinson", 1974 Jan 27 (Box 43)
      - Linda Kipps and Robert Fisher, "6 poems by Emily Dickinson", 1977 May 9 (Box 43)
      - Marilee Skidmore and John Metz, "6 poems by Emily Dickinson", 1976 Jan 30 (Box 43)
      - Barbara Lister-Sink, "4 poems by Emily Dickinson", 1976 Oct 3 (Box 43)
      - Phalen Tassie, 4 songs, 1956 May 29 (Box 43)
      - Lynn Meyers, John D'Armand, "Stopping by Woods and 3 Epitaphs", undated (Box 43)
      - Marilee Skidmore, "From the Sea", 1981? Jun 26 (Box 43)
      - Don Boothman and Russell Woolen, 4 songs, 1970 Apr 6 (Box 43)
      - Jeanette Hubert and Constance LaSalle, "3 poems by Mary Lillian Fortson.", 1971 May 2 (Box 43)
    - Choral Works
      - "0 Sing Unto the Lord a New Song," Smith College Glee Club, 1955 Jun 4 (Box 43)
      - "A Christmas Hymn," Hampshire Choral Society, 1973 Dec 9 (Box 43)
      - 0, Sing Unto the Lord a New Song, 1955 Jan 3 (Box 43)
    - Symphonic Works
      - "Concerto for Piano and Strings," Robert Miller, 1967 Apr 9 (Box 43)
    - Dramatic Works
      - "Captain Lovelock," Pacific Lyric Theatre, 1980 Sep (Box 43)
      - "The Sire de Maletroit," Seagle Colony, undated (Box 43)
      - "The Sire de Maletroit," WNYC Festival, 1959 Feb 21 (Box 43)
      - "The Yankee Pedlar," Seagle Colony (2 tapes), 1962 Aug 17 (Box 43)
      - "The Yankee Pedlar," AMCOP (4 tapes), 1964 Apr 25 (Box 43)
    - Solo Pieces and Chamber Music
      - "Suite for Viola Alone", Louise Rood (2 tapes), undated (Box 43)
      - "Fantasy in A" for violin and piano, Phillipp Naegele and John Duke (2 performances), 1965 (Box 43)
      - "Narrative" for viola and piano, Ernst and Lory Wallfisch, 1975 Dec 14 (Box 43)
      - Cello and piano piece (unidentified) (Box 43)
      - Trios, 1965 Nov (Box 43)
      - "Trio in D-major," Smith College, 1966 Jan 16 (Box 43)
      - "Trio in D-major," Phillipp Naegele, William Schultz, and John Duke, undated (Box 43)
    - Miscellaneous
      - WBUR Composer 7 S Forum, n. d. (Box 43)
      - Retirement Party, 1967 May 20 (Box 44)
    - Piano Performances by John Duke
      - Schubert, Bizet, Moussorgsky, Bach, Couperin (2 tapes), 1965 Sep 26 (Box 44)
      - Ravel, Couperin, Scarlatti, n. d. (Box 44)
      - Alvin Etler Sonata, n. d. (Box 44)
      - Chopin program ( 2 tapes), n. d. (Box 44)
      - Beethoven op. 110 sonata, 1964 Feb 23 (Box 44)
      - Mendelssohn piano concerto with the Smith-Amherst orchestra (Box 44)
  - Tapes: Cassettes
    - Songs
      - Don Boothman, undated (Box 44)
      - Anne Cotton, Barbara Hardgrave, John Duke, 1982 Oct 5 (Box 44)
      - Ann Zibelman, 6 songs, undated (Box 44)
      - Susan Whitenack, 1978 Apr 9 (Box 44)
      - Raren Ranung Studio, 1984 Apr 28 (Box 44)
      - John Duke Concert, 1983 Jan 28 (Box 44)
      - Unidentified, 1984 Sept 8 (Box 44)
      - Karen Ranung Studio, song recital and "Captain Lovelock", 1980 (Box 44)
      - Song recital, Sage Hall, 1980 Aug 21 (Box 44)
      - Karen Ranung Studio, 1982 Mar 27 (Box 44)
      - Karen Ranung and John Duke, 1982 Apr 24 (Box 44)
      - Patricia Kennedy and Doris Drew, 1978 Apr 21 (Box 44)
      - Festival, Pierce Memorial Chapel (2 tapes), 1983 May 26 (Box 44)
      - Celebration, Ball State University, 1983 Nov 4 (Box 44)
      - D'Anna Fortunato, n. d. (Box 44)
      - Songs and String Quartet, 1982 Dec 1 (Box 44)
      - Shirley Westwood and Kenneth Griffiths, 1984 Oct 26 (Box 44)
      - Cheryl Boyd-Waddell, "4 poems of Emily Dickinson", 1984 May 17 (Box 44)
      - Karen Smith, "4 Chinese Love Lyrics", undated (Box 44)
    - Choral Works
      - "O, Sing Unto the Lord a New Song," Smith College, 1980 Apr 20 (Box 44)
    - Dramatic Works
      - "Captain Lovelock" rehearsal, Pacific Lyric Theatre, undated (Box 44)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Shirley Westwood recital (no Duke on program), 1980; 1981 (Box 44)
      - Del-Louise Moyer recital (no Duke on program), n. d. (Box 44)
      - "Love Among the Ruins," Faculty Show, 1952 (Box 44)
      - Sarah Bloxham concert (no Duke on program), 1982 Jul 17 (Box 44)
      - Out But Not Down Club meeting, talk about faculty shows by Duke, 1982 May 10 (Box 44)
      - Mary Lillian Fortson senior piano recital (student of Duke), 1983 Nov 29 (Box 44)
      - Miscellaneous chamber music (no Duke works), n. d. (Box 44)
  - Tapes: Discs
    - Songs
      - No. 18-20, 23, "2 songs for Baritone, "Trio in G major"; WNYC Composers Forum (10 sides), 1939 Sep 14 (Box 45)
      - No. 7, 9, 11, 17, performed by Benjamin DeLoache (multiple copies), undated (Box 45)
      - No. 38, 47 performed by Nathan Price and Edna Phillips (2 sides), 1949 Dec 14 (Box 45)
    - Symphonic Works
      - "Concerto for Piano and Strings," WQXR (5 sides), 1944 Oct 29 (Box 45)
    - Solo Pieces and Chamber Music
      - "Suite for Viola Alone" performed by Louise Rood (2 sides), undated (Box 45)
      - "Rondo in B~ for piano by John Duke; "Waltz in A-flat" by Frederic Chopin, performed by John Duke, 1939 Sep 30 (Box 45)
      - "Aria for Cello Alone," "Chinese Opera" by Otto Luening performed at Yaddo (2 sides), undated (Box 45)
      - "Melody in E-flat" for cello and piano performed by Marion DeRonde and John Duke, "Rondo in B" for piano performed by John Duke (2 sides--2 copies), undated (Box 45)
      - "Trio" (4 sides), undated (Box 45)
        See also: songs above
      - "String Quartet" performed by the Smith College String Quartet (4 sides), undated (Box 45)
    - Miscellaneous
      - "Love Among the Ruins," Faculty Show (2 sides), 1952 (Box 45)
      - "Sonata for Piano and Violin" by Elliott Griffis, WNYG Composers Forum (5 sides), undated (Box 45)